人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译 Silmar
翻译 小舞
翻译 小熊嘟嘟
翻译 尼克白
翻译 树树
翻译 潇湘月影
翻译 泰斯
校对 泰斯·雪诺
校对 Silmar
时间轴 崽猪
时间轴 加森
时间轴 全家筒
顾问 屈畅(ccxx)
特效/后期 鱼骨头
特效/后期 拉图
总监 泰斯·雪诺
改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第四季 第十集
你又穿起黑斗篷了
You're wearing a black cloak again.
他们派我来跟你谈判
I've been sent to negotiate with you.
看来我又吃了轻信的亏
It appears my trusting nature got the better of me.
这亏我从前也吃过
It's happened before.
你前来投诚时
I was hoping your loyalty was real
我曾希望你是忠诚的  琼恩·雪诺
when you pledged yourself to us, Jon Snow.
我真心希望
Truly I was.
断掌命令我加入你们的队伍
The Halfhand ordered me to join your army
带着得到的情报回到黑城堡
and bring back whatever information I could to Castle Black.
他逼我杀死他赢取你们的信任
He made me kill him so you'd trust me.
我是忠诚的
I was loyal...
忠于他  忠于守夜人的誓言
to him and to my Night's Watch vows.
每一条誓言吗
All your vows?
她不足以改变你的心志  是吧
She wasn't enough to turn you, eh?
你足以改变她吗
Were you enough to turn her?
我逃走时她射了我三箭
She put three arrows in me when I escaped.
你在黑城堡见到她了吗
Did you see her again at Castle Black?
-见到了  -然后呢
- Yes. - And?
她死了
She's dead.
-是你下的手  -不是
- Your doing? - No.
我们敬她一杯
We'll drink to her.
我要杀你法子多得是
Of all the ways I'd kill you,
下毒是最不可能的
poison would be the last.
-耶哥蕊特  -耶哥蕊特
- Ygritte. - Ygritte.
这不是红酒
That's not wine.
对  这是正宗的北方酒  琼恩·雪诺
No, it's a proper northern drink, Jon Snow.
你们很棒  打得顽强
You did well. Fought hard.
杀了几个我们最强壮的人
Killed some of our strongest men.
一个巨人冲进你们的隧道
One of our giants went into your tunnel
再也没出来
and never came out again.
强壮的玛格
Mag the Mighty.
他死了
He's dead.
他杀了我的朋友葛兰
He killed my friend Grenn.
他是巨人的国王
He was their king.
是古老家族的最后传人
The last of a bloodline that stretches back
血统比先民更久远
before the First Men.
葛兰来自某个农场
Grenn came from a farm.
-玛格和葛兰  -葛兰和玛格
- Mag and Grenn. - Grenn and Mag.
库柏克  能给弄点儿吃的吗
Kullback, could I trouble you for something to eat?
我想我们的客人很长时间没吃东西了
I don't imagine our guest has eaten anything for quite some time.
你是来谈条件的
So, you're here to strike a bargain?
全体调头  回老家去
Turn your army around and go home.
你明知我清楚你们箭矢不足
You know I know you're low on arrows,
油料耗尽  人手短缺
you're low on oil, you're low on men.
还剩多少人  有五十吗
How many are left, 50?
我告诉托蒙德和欧瑞尔
I told Tormund and Orell.
我们有一千多人
We have more than 1,000 men.
我的实力你都看到了
I showed you everything I had.
全军总数超过十万
The whole army, 100,000 strong.
你们做了什么呢  倾尽全力阻击我们
And what did you do? You fired on us with everything you had.
毛毛雨而已
It wasn't much.
我看清情况之后
As soon as I saw that,
马上派了四百人去爬过长城
I sent 400 men to climb the Wall,
西边五哩无人守卫的位置
an unmanned stretch five miles west of here.
许多人会死在攀爬途中
A lot of them will die climbing,
但是今天晚上  大部分能越过长城
but most of them will be over by the end of the day.
我这是对你实话实说  琼恩·雪诺
It's me being honest with you, Jon Snow,
我待你远比你待我真诚得多
which is more than you've ever done for me.
我的人民已经流了太多血
My people have bled enough.
我们此来不是为了征服
We're not here to conquer.
我们要去你们的长城后面躲避
We're here to hide behind your Wall.
和你们一样  我们需要你们的隧道
Just like you. We need your tunnel.
我们都知道  凛冬将至
Now we both know that winter is coming.
要是冬天真正来临  我的人民没到长城以南
And if my people aren't south of the Wall when it comes in earnest,
我们都会落得比死亡更凄惨
we'll all end up worse than dead.
你想跟我谈条件
You want to strike a bargain with me?
这是我的条件
Here's the bargain.
你回去  为我们敞开大门
You go back, you open the gates to us,
我可以发誓不会再死一个人
and I swear to you that no one else will die.
若拒绝
Refuse,
我们就把黑城堡守军斩尽杀绝
and we'll kill every last man at Castle Black.
原来这才是你的目的
Oh, that's why you're here.
我料想你能够得手  他们来不及阻止你
I reckon you could do it before any of them could stop you.
他们自然会杀掉你
They'd kill you, of course.
慢慢折磨死你
They'd kill you slow.
可你进门之时早就知道了
But you knew that when you came in here.
你下得了手吗  琼恩·雪诺
Are you capable of that, Jon Snow?
将与你和谈之人斩杀在他的营帐里
Killing a man in his own tent when he's just offered you peace?
守夜人是这样的军团吗
Is that what the Night's Watch is?
你是这样的人吗
Is that what you are?
骑兵来袭
Riders coming!
-是你们偷袭  -不是
- Are you attacking us? - No.
你自己也说了  我们人手不够
It's like you said, we don't have the men.
稳住  向我靠拢  靠拢
Hold! To me! To me!
退后
Stand down!
我说我的人民已经流了太多血
I said my people have bled enough
我是认真的
and I meant it.
把他们围起来
Round them up.
你是塞外之王
You're the King-beyond-the-Wall?
-知道我是谁吗  -无幸得知
- Do you know who I am? - Never had the pleasure.
你面前的是史坦尼斯·拜拉席恩
This is Stannis Baratheon,
七国唯一的真王
the one true king of the Seven Kingdoms.
我们不在七国之内
We're not in the Seven Kingdoms
你穿得也不合时宜
and you're not dressed for this weather.
向国王投降通常应当下跪
It is customary to kneel when surrendering to a king.
我们从不下跪
We do not kneel.
天黑前  我会抓到数千俘虏
I'll have thousands of your men in chains by nightfall,
没地方安置  也没东西给他们吃
have nowhere to put them, have nothing to feed them.
我此来并不想赶尽杀绝
I'm not here to slaughter beat dogs.
他们的命运掌握在他们的国王手里
Their fate depends on their king.
还是一样  我们从不下跪
All the same, we do not kneel.
把他们带走
Take these men away.
守夜人的汉子到野人营地里做什么
What's a man of the Night's Watch doing in a wildling camp?
我是受命前来和塞外之王谈判的
I was sent to discuss terms with the King-beyond-the-Wall.
你面前的是唯一的真王  小子
You're speaking to the one true king, boy.
你要尊称他为陛下
You will address him as Your Grace.
我知道他是国王  我父亲就是因他而死
I know he's the king. My father died for him.
我叫琼恩·雪诺  陛下
My name is Jon Snow, Your Grace.
我是奈德·史塔克的儿子
I'm Ned Stark's son.
你父亲是一位可敬的人
Your father was an honorable man.
是的  陛下
He was, Your Grace.
你认为你父亲会怎么处理他呢
What do you think he'd have done with him?
我曾是这个人的囚犯
I was this man's prisoner once.
他可以折磨我  可以杀死我
He could have tortured me. He could have killed me.
但是他饶了我的命
But he spared my life.
我想我父亲会把他关起来
I think my father would have taken him prisoner,
再听听他的解释
listened to what he had to say.
很好  带他走
Very well, then. Take him.
陛下
Your Grace.
如果我父亲见过我所见过的事
If my father had seen the things that I've seen,
他还会建议您天黑前将尸体烧掉
he'd also tell you to burn the dead before nightfall.
所有的尸体
All of them.
我想用罂粟花奶
I would suggest milk of the poppy
来缓解他的疼痛  可他完全没有知觉
to ease his pain, but he is completely insensate.
该死的马泰尔
Bloody Martells.
他中的应该是狮身蝎尾兽之毒
The cause appears to be manticore venom.
是的  死亡之首狮身蝎尾兽
It is. The Death's Head manticore.
我看过很多关于它的资料
Yes, I've read a great deal about it.
是一种很可怕的毒药
It's a horrible poison.
原产自曼塔芮
Usually Mantari in origin.
好了  好了
Oh! Yes, yes.
我们已经无能为力了
There's nothing to be done.
不  还有希望
Yes, there is.
我能问问你知道你在做什么吗
May I ask what you think you're doing?
救他
Saving him.
陛下  我也不希望这样
Your Grace, I wish it were otherwise,
但格雷果爵士已经没救了
but Ser Gregor is beyond saving.
完全没救
Well, well beyond.
此人根本不是学士
This man is not even a maester,
更别说大学士了
let alone Grand Maester.
这样最好
That's for the best.
没有学士知道该怎么救他
No maester knows how to save him.
就是因为这种傲慢
That is exactly the sort of arrogance
他才被驱逐出学城  陛下
that had him expelled from the Citadel, Your Grace.
他的好奇心既危险又变态
His curiosity was deemed dangerous and unnatural.
我认为这是客观的说法
Rightly so, in my opinion.
退下吧  大学士
You're dismissed, Grand Maester.
但是  陛下  这里是我的实验室
But, Your Grace, this is my laboratory.
-不再是了  -但我...
- Not anymore. - But I--
-你能救他吗  -很难说  陛下
- You can save him? - Difficult to say, Your Grace.
但如果我过去的实验可以借鉴
But if my past work is any guide...
我们还有机会
...we stand a chance.
尽全力吧
Do everything you can.
需要什么尽管找我
Come to me for anything you need.
非常感谢  陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
您应该知道
You should know,
这个治疗过程可能会改变他...
the process may change him...
某些方面
somewhat.
会让他变弱吗
Will it weaken him?
不会的
Oh, no.
那就好
Very well, then.
不要再说了
Not another word.
我们已经讨论过了  不再重提
We've been over this. The matter's closed.
我就要重提
I'm opening it again.
你和洛拉斯·提利尔订了婚
You were betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
你现在仍和洛拉斯·提利尔有婚约
You're still betrothed to Loras Tyrell.
等托曼和玛格丽一完婚
And you will marry Loras Tyrell
你就嫁给洛拉斯·提利尔
as soon as Tommen marries Margaery.
我不嫁
I will not.
詹姆不能娶妻或继承封地
Jaime cannot marry or inherit lands.
提利昂明天就要行刑
Tyrion's sentence will be carried out tomorrow.
你好几次信誓旦旦地声称
You have on several occasions made great claims
要为家族的未来做出贡献
about your commitment to this family's future.
你在家族未来中的角色
Your role in that future
从未像现在这样重要过
is more vital now than it ever was.
我不在乎
I don't care.
我要留在君临
I will stay in King's Landing
留在我的儿子  我的国王身边
where I belong with my son the king.
你九岁那年  我奉诏要来君临
When you were nine years old, I was called to the capital.
我本打算要带你弟弟留下你
I decided to take your brother with me and not you.
你偏说什么无论如何
You insisted that you would not be left at Casterly Rock
你也不留在凯岩城  如果你还记得...
under any circumstances. And if you recall--
我没兴趣听您拿那些陈年旧事
I'm not interested in hearing another one of your smug stories
耀武扬威
about the time you won.
今非昔比  这次不一样
This isn't going to be one of those times.
你以为你会是第一个
Do you think you'll be the first person
被拖进圣堂成亲的女人吗
dragged into a sept to be married against her will?
您记不记得  当年您走进王座厅
When you marched into the throne room to tell me
告诉我黑水湾大战胜利之时
we'd won the Battle of Blackwater-- do you remember?
我和托曼坐在铁王座上
I was sitting on the Iron Throne with Tommen.
我正要喂他夜影之水
I was about to give him essence of nightshade.
为了不让坏人抢走我的孩子
That's how far I was willing to go when I thought
我可以不择手段
someone awful had come to take my son away.
而现在就有坏人来抢他了
Someone awful is coming to take him away.
-没有的事  -乔佛里已经死了
- No. - Joffrey is dead.
弥赛菈像牲口一样被卖走
Myrcella's been sold like livestock.
如今您又要把我送去高庭  偷走我儿子
And now you want to ship me off to Highgarden and steal my boy.
我仅剩的儿子
My last boy.
玛格丽张牙舞爪
Margaery will dig her claws in,
您也张牙舞爪  你俩为了争夺他
you will dig your claws in and you'll fight over him
势必要把他扯个身首分离
like beasts until you rip him apart.
哪怕毁掉整个家族我也要阻止这种事发生
I will burn our house to the ground before I let that happen.
你打算怎么毁
And how will you do that?
我要将真相公之于众
I'll tell everyone the truth.
敢问什么真相
What truth would that be?
您不知道是吗
You don't know, do you?
您从来都不信
You never believed it.
这怎么可能
How is that possible?
瞧我说的什么话  当然可能了
What am I saying? Of course it's possible.
一个满脑子只有家族宏图愿景的人
How can someone so consumed by the idea of his family
哪能知道现实之中的家人在做什么呢
have any conception what his actual family was doing?
我们就在您面前  您却视而不见
We were right there in front of you and you didn't see us.
过去这二十年间
One look in the past 20 years,
您若仔细瞧过自己的孩子们一眼  就会知道
one real look at your own children and you would have known.
知道什么
Known what?
传言都是真的
Everything they say is true.
-詹姆和我的传言  -不
- About Jaime and me. - No.
-您的千秋家业只是谎言  -不  不
- Your legacy is a lie. - No, no, no, no.
我不相信你
I don't believe you.
不  您信了
Yes, you do.
詹姆
Jaime.
你赢了
You won.
少了一个弟弟  很得意吧
One fewer brother. Must be proud of yourself.
是不是就没有你做不出的事
There's really nothing you wouldn't do, is there?
为了家人  是的
For my family, no, nothing.
为了家人  我可以做出你想都不敢想的事
I would do things for my family you couldn't imagine.
-提利昂就是家人  -他不是
- Tyrion is your family. - He's not.
-你没得选  -可以选  你也可以
- You don't get to choose. - I do. So do you.
你可以选那个
You can choose the creature
害死母亲来到世上的怪物
that killed our mother to come into this world--
你疯了  这种事也怪到他头上吗
Are you really mad enough to blame him for that?
他又没想害死母亲  他还是个婴儿
He didn't decide to kill her. He was an infant.
疾病也没想害死人
A disease doesn't decide to kill you.
可你还是治好了病  没等它害死你
All the same, you cut it out before it does.
你要怎样做  你怎么选
What do you decide? What do you choose?
我为了回来见你
The things I did to get back to you,
经受那么多磨难  结果却发现你...
to endure all that, only to find you--
我选择了你
I choose you.
-你只会说  -没错
- Those are words. - Yes.
我刚跟父亲也说了
Like the ones I just said to Father.
我告诉他了
I told him.
告诉他什么
Told him what?
我们的事
I told him about us.
你说了
You told him?
我告诉他我不会嫁给洛拉斯·提利尔
I told him I won't marry Loras Tyrell.
我要留下来陪着托曼和你
I told him I'm staying right here with Tommen, with you.
你觉得他会接受吗
You think he'll just accept that?
你去问他
Go and ask him.
你怎么说的
What did you say?
我现在不想谈泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't want to talk about Tywin Lannister.
我选的不是泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't choose Tywin Lannister.
我爱的不是泰温·兰尼斯特
I don't love Tywin Lannister.
我爱的是我的弟弟
I love my brother.
我爱的是我的爱人
I love my lover.
人们会传播流言  在背后取笑
People will whisper, they'll make their jokes.
随他们去吧
Let them.
他们太渺小  我根本看不见
They're all so small, I can't even see them.
我眼里只有我在意的
I only see what matters.
万一有人进来
Someone will walk in.
我不在乎
I don't care.
在你面前的正是风暴降生丹妮莉丝
不焚者
弥林女王
安达尔  罗伊拿人和先民的女王
草海上的卡丽熙
解放者  龙之母
陛下亲自接见  我很是感激
我叫费南斯
陛下若是喜欢  我可以说通用语
I can speak the common tongue if you wish.
你说得很好
You speak it very well.
陛下还我自由前  我归米戈达尔伟主所有
Before you freed me, I belonged to Master Mighdal.
我是他家孩子的先生
I was tutor to his children.
教授语言和历史
I taught them languages and history.
他们从我这里知道许多关于陛下家族的故事
They know a great deal about your family because of me.
小卡拉才七岁
Little Calla is only seven,
但她非常敬慕您
but she admires you very much.
我希望可以当得起她的敬慕
I hope I can prove worthy of her admiration.
有什么可以为你做的
What can I do for you?
当您攻下本城之时  孩子们请求我
When you took the city, the children begged me
别离开他们家
not to leave the house.
但米戈达尔伟主和我都认为我必须走
But Master Mighdal and I agreed that I must.
所以我无家可归
So I lost my home.
现在流落街头
Now I live on the streets.
我有设施齐全的饭堂
I have outfitted mess halls
可供所有曾经的奴隶果腹
to feed all former slaves
还有棚屋给他们居住
and barracks to shelter them.
我无意冒犯  陛下
I do not mean to offend, Your Grace.
我去过其中一处
I went to one of these places.
见到青壮年抢老人的东西
The young prey on the old.
他们想要什么就抢
Take what they want
稍遇反抗  就是拳打脚踢
and beat us if we resist.
我马上派无垢者去保障饭堂治安
My Unsullied will make them safe again in short order,
我的朋友  我向你保证
my friend, this I promise you.
就算饭堂安全了  那我又算什么呢
Even if they are safe, who would I be there?
我活着又有什么意义呢
What purpose would I serve?
在伟主家  我是教师
With my master, I was a teacher.
受到他孩子的尊敬和爱戴
I had the respect and love of his children.
那你想要我怎么做
What is it that you want from me?
陛下  我请求您
Your Grace, I ask you
准我卖身给米戈达尔伟主
to let me sell myself back to Master Mighdal.
你希望回到剥夺你自由的人身边
You want to return to a man who owned you
为他做牛做马
like a goat or a chair?
求您了  陛下
Please, Your Grace.
那些年轻人或许为您建立的新世界欣喜若狂
The young may rejoice in the new world you have built for them,
但我们太老了  经不起折腾
but for those of us too old to change,
只感到恐惧和悲惨
there is only fear and squalor.
不止我一个人这么想
I am not alone.
还有很多人等在外面  向您提出同样的请求
There are many outside waiting to beg the same of you.
我夺下这座城
I did not take this city
是要改变不公的世道  而不是因循守旧
to preside over the injustice I fought to destroy.
我是为了给人们带来自由
I took it to bring people freedom.
但自由就意味着  你们可以自行选择
But freedom means making your own choices.
我准许你和你的前伟主签署合约
I will allow you to sign a contract with your former master.
时限不能超过一年
It may not cover a period lasting longer than a year.
谢谢您  陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢
Thank you.
伟主们会趁机利用这种局面
The masters will take advantage of this situation.
服侍他们的人
The men serving them
本质上还是奴隶  只不过换了种说法
will be slaves in all but name.
上前来  我的朋友
Approach, my friend.
我听不懂  女王陛下
女王要你上前说话
我带来了...
I have brought you--
他从天而降
He came from the sky.
黑色的
The black one.
长翅膀的影子
The winged shadow.
他从天而降
He came from the sky and...
我的女儿
My girl.
我的小女儿
My little girl.
她叫什么
What was her name?
扎拉  陛下
Zala, Your Grace.
-她多大了  -三岁
- How old was she? - Three.
三岁
Three.
还是没有卓耿的消息吗
有水手三天前看到他飞过黛壁  女王陛下
那之后就再无消息了
来陵寝找我
他们来自七国各地
They came to us
从白港到荒冢屯
from White Harbor and Barrowton,
从美人市集到君临
from Fairmarket and King's Landing,
从东南西北
from north and south,
来到此处
from east and west.
他们为了保护那些永远不会知道他们姓名的
They died protecting men, women, and children
男女老少而死
who will never know their names.
我们自当铭记他们
It is for us to remember them.
我们的兄弟
Our brothers,
我们再难见到如此之人
we shall never see their like again.
他们的守望至死方休  于斯结束
And now their watch is ended.
那个老瞎子给我包扎了伤口
Your old blind man patched me up.
为什么
Why?
他发过誓  要医治所有伤员  无论敌我
He's sworn to treat all wounded men, friend or foe.
你希望我活下来  好折磨我吗
You want me alive so you can torture me?
没人会折磨你
No one's gonna torture you.
那你们准备怎么处决我们  吊死  砍头
So how do we die? Hanging? Beheading?
还是把我们从长城顶上扔下去
Drop us from the top of the Wall?
我不知道会怎样处置犯人
I don't know what happens to the prisoners.
那做决定的是谁
Who decides?
我想应该是史坦尼斯
I suppose Stannis does.
他现在是你的国王了吗
He your king now?
我不效忠任何国王
I don't have a king.
你和我们待太久了  琼恩·雪诺
You spent too much time with us, Jon Snow.
你再也不会向任何人下跪了
You can never be a kneeler again.
我们会火化你们那帮人的尸体
We're gonna burn the bodies of your dead.
你有话想跟他们说吗
Do you want to say any words over them?
说话  说什么话
Words? What kind of words?
悼词  我不知道自由民是怎么做的
Funeral words. I don't know how the free folk do it.
什么怎么做的
Do what?
永别
Say farewell.
死人可听不到我们说话  小子
The dead can't hear us, boy.
雪诺
Snow.
你爱过她吗
Did you love her?
她很爱你
She loved you.
她告诉你的
She told you?
没有
No.
她成天都在说要怎么杀了你
All she ever talked about was killing you.
所以我知道
That's how I know.
她属于北方
She belongs in the North.
真正的北方
The real North.
懂我意思吗
You understand me?
我们可以停下来休息一会儿
We can stop. We can rest.
找到三眼乌鸦再休息
We'll rest with the three-eyed raven.
我们到不了的
We're not going to make it.
我们已经到了
We're already here.
玖健
Jojen.
看  玖健  你看
Look, Jojen. Look.
玖健  加把劲
Jojen! Come on!
去帮他们  快
Help them! Now!
抓住我
Hold on to me!
坚持住
Hang on!
-阿多  -去帮他们
- Hodor. - Help them!
阿多
Hodor.
Hodor!
阿多
Hodor.
Hodor!
布兰
Bran!
快去救你自己
Save yourself, now!
跟我来  布兰登·史塔克
Come with me, Brandon Stark.
他没救了
He is lost.
跟我来  或陪他死
Come with me or die with him.
跟他们走
Go with them.
它们没法跟进来
They cannot follow us.
驱动它们的力量在这里无效
The power that moves them is powerless here.
你是谁
Who are you?
先民称我们为孩子
The First Men called us the children,
但我们的诞生比他们早得多
but we were born long before them.
跟我来  他在等你
Come, he waits for you.
您就是三眼乌鸦吗
You're the three-eyed raven?
我有过诸多经历
I've been many things.
现在的我是这副模样
Now I am what you see.
我弟弟指引我们找到您  现在他...
My brother, he led us to you and now he--
他知道将发生什么
He knew what would happen.
从他出发的那一刻
From the moment he left,
他就知道了  可他还是去了
he knew and he went anyway.
您怎么知道
How do you know?
我一直在观察你们
I've been watching you.
你们所有人
All of you.
你们的人生
All of your lives.
用我一千零一只眼睛
With 1,000 eyes and one.
现在你终于来到我面前
Now you've come to me at last,
布兰登·史塔克
Brandon Stark.
尽管来得有些迟
Though the hour is late.
我不希望任何人因我而死
I didn't want anyone to die for me.
他为帮你找回你失去的东西而死
He died so you could find what you have lost.
您能治好我的腿吗
You're going to help me walk again?
你永远无法行走了
You will never walk again.
但你可以飞
But you will fly.
波德瑞克
Podrick.
马哪儿去了
Where are the horses?
我昨晚明明把它们绊起来了
I hobbled them last night.
怎么绊的
What sort of hobble?
八字结  您教过我的那种
A figure eight like you taught me.
如果你是按我教的方法绊的
If you did it like I taught you,
马应该还在这
then the horses would be here.
也许被贼偷了
Thieves, maybe?
从这里到鹰巢城至少有三十哩
It's at least 30 miles to the Eyrie from here.
你负责背鞍囊
You're carrying the saddlebags.
有人来了
People coming.
你等会儿再拉屎吧  有人来了
You can shit later. There's people coming.
早上好
Morning.
你的剑不错
I like your sword.
这儿离血门是不是很近了
Are we getting close to the Bloody Gate?
再走十哩
About 10 more miles.
你听到了吗  波德瑞克
Did you hear that, Podrick?
离血门只有十哩了
Only 10 more miles to the Bloody Gate.
你是骑士吗
Are you a knight?
不是
No.
但你知道如何使剑
But you know how to use that sword?
没错
I do.
它有名字吗
Does it have a name?
守誓剑
Oathkeeper.
我的叫缝衣针
Mine's Needle.
好名字
Good name.
谁教你武艺
Who taught you how to fight?
我父亲
My father.
我父亲不想教我
Mine never wanted to.
他说打斗是男孩子的事
Said fighting was for boys.
我父亲也是
Mine said the same.
但我还是跟男孩子们打
But I kept fighting the boys anyway.
屡战屡败
Kept losing.
最后我父亲说  "如果你要打
Finally my father said, "If you're going to do it,
不妨打得像样些"
you might as well do it right."
七神保佑
Seven blessings.
我是塔斯的布蕾妮  他是波德瑞克·派恩
I'm Brienne of Tarth. This is Podrick Payne.
你有事吗
You want something?
那是桑铎·克里冈  猎狗
That's Sandor Clegane. The Hound.
你是艾莉亚·史塔克
You're Arya Stark.
我问你有何贵干
I asked if you wanted something.
我向你母亲发过誓要带你回家
I swore to your mother I would bring you home to her.
我母亲死了
My mother's dead.
我知道
I know.
只愿我当时能在场保护她
I wish I could have been there to protect her.
你不是北方人
You're not a northerner.
不是  但我立下了神圣的誓言要保护她
No, but I swore a sacred vow to protect her.
那你为什么没做到
Why didn't you?
她命我押送詹姆·兰尼斯特回君临
She commanded me to bring Jaime Lannister back to King's Landing.
你被兰尼斯特收买了
You're paid by the Lannisters.
你是来取我的人头回去领赏的吧
You're here for the bounty on me.
我没有被兰尼斯特收买
I'm not paid by the Lannisters.
是吗
No?
你手里那把剑不错啊
Fancy sword you've got there.
哪儿来的
Where'd you get it?
我看了一辈子的兰尼斯特金子
I've been looking at Lannister gold all my life.
说啊  狗日塔斯的布蕾妮
Go on, Brienne of fucking Tarth.
告诉我它不是兰尼斯特家的金子
Tell me that's not Lannister gold.
詹姆·兰尼斯特将这把剑给了我
Jaime Lannister gave me this sword.
十哩之外就是血门
The Bloody Gate is 10 miles.
我在旧神面前向你母亲发誓
I swore to your mother by the old gods--
我不关心你发什么誓
I don't care what you swore.
-艾莉亚  -你听见她说的了
- Arya! - You heard the girl.
-她不会跟你走的  -她要跟我走
- She's not coming with you. - She is.
你不太听得懂人话啊
You're not a good listener.
瓦雷利亚钢
That Valyrian steel?
我一直都想要把瓦雷利亚钢剑
I always wanted some Valyrian steel.
跟我走吧  艾莉亚  我带你去安全的地方
Come with me, Arya. I'll take you to safety.
安全  哪里还他妈的安全
Safety? Where the fuck's that?
她鹰巢城的姨妈死了  她妈死了
Her aunt in the Eyrie is dead. Her mother's dead.
她爸死了  她哥死了
Her father's dead. Her brother's dead.
临冬城就是一片废墟
Winterfell is a pile of rubble.
没有哪儿安全了  你这蠢娘们儿
There is no safety, you dumb bitch.
你到现在还没搞明白
You don't know that by now,
你不是照看她的合适人选
you're the wrong one to watch over her.
那你现在所做的
And that's what you're doing?
是在照看她吗
Watching over her?
对  这正是我所做的
Aye, that's what I'm doing.
我没打算杀你  爵士先生
I have no wish to kill you, Ser.
我不是什么骑士
I'm not a knight.
艾莉亚
Arya!
-她人呢  -刚还在这儿
- Where is she? - She was just here.
你怎么不看着她
Why weren't you watching her?
我看着你呢  我怕你需要帮忙
I was watching you. I thought you might need some help.
哪条路  她往哪条路走了  波德
Which way, Pod? Which way did she go?
我想是那边
I think that way.
艾莉亚
Arya!
你还没走
You still here?
大块头娘们儿救了你
Big bitch saved you.
我不需要人救
I don't need saving.
是的  你不需要  你是个真正的杀手
No, not you. You're a real killer.
你有那什么水之舞
With your water dancing
还有缝衣针
and your Needle.
你会死吗
You gonna die?
除非从岩石后面跳出来个学士
Unless there's a maester hiding behind that rock,
的确
aye,
我要死了
I'm done.
我真他妈想来口酒
I'd skin you alive for wine.
不要水
Fuck water.
给一个娘们儿干掉了
Killed by a woman.
你指定很喜欢这结局
I bet you like that.
去吧
Go on,
跟她走吧
go after her.
她会帮你的
She'll help you.
只身一人
Going it alone,
你撑不过一天
you won't last a day out there.
我会撑得比你久
I'll last longer than you.
还记得心脏所在的位置吗
You remember where the heart is?
动手吧
Fuck it.
我准备好了
I'm ready.
来吧  小狼女
Go on, girl.
你的名单上又少了一个
Another name off your list.
你一直跟我念叨的
You kept promising me.
我杀了你的屠夫小弟
I cut down your butcher's boy.
那个红毛
The ginger.
他当时求我饶他一命
He was begging for mercy.
"求求你  爵士  不要杀我
"Please, Ser. Please don't kill me.
求求你"
Please, please."
血溅了我的马一身
Bled all over my horse.
弄得我的马鞍好久都是他的臭味儿
Saddle stunk of butcher's boy for weeks.
还有你姐姐
And your sister.
你漂亮的姐姐
Your pretty sister.
我应该上她的
I should have taken her.
黑水湾大火那一晚
That night the Blackwater burned.
我应该狠狠地上她
I should have fucked her bloody.
至少我也有个美好的回忆
At least I'd have one happy memory.
你想让我乞求吗
Do I have to beg you?
动手吧
Do it.
动手啊
杀了我
Kill me.
Kill me!
杀了我
噢  快动手啊  烂婊子养的野种
Oh, get on with it, you son of a whore.
如此评价咱们的母亲大人
Is that any way to speak about our mother?
你来做什么
What are you doing?
你以为我来做什么
What do you think I'm doing?
河边有条划桨船  开往自由贸易城邦
A galley's waiting in the bay bound for the Free Cities.
-谁在帮忙  -瓦里斯
- Who's helping you? - Varys.
-瓦里斯  -你的朋友远比你以为的多
- Varys? - You have more friends than you thought.
楼梯顶上那扇门锁着
There's a locked door at the top of the stairs.
敲两下  然后再敲两下
Knock on it twice, then twice again.
瓦里斯就会开门
Varys will open.
那么就此告别了
I suppose this is good-bye, then.
永别了  小弟弟
Farewell, little brother.
詹姆
Jaime.
谢谢你救了我的命
Thank you for my life.
快走
Quickly now.
泰温
Tywin?
我的雄狮
My lion.
对不起
I'm sorry.
提利昂
Tyrion.
放下弩弓
Put down the crossbow.
谁放你的
Who released you?
是你哥哥吧  我想
Your brother, I expect.
他一直对你心软
He always had a soft spot for you.
来  我们去卧室好好谈
Come, we'll go and talk in my chambers.
你打算这样跟我谈吗
This is how you want to speak to me, hmm?
你最喜欢让你父亲蒙羞
Shaming your father has always given you pleasure.
从我出生起
All my life
您就想要我死
you've wanted me dead.
是的
Yes.
但你不愿意死
But you refused to die.
我尊重这一点
I respect that.
甚至有点佩服
Even admire it.
你为了属于你的一切而战斗
You fight for what's yours.
我不会让他们处死你
I'd never let them execute you.
你就是害怕这个吗
Is that what you fear?
我不会让伊林·派恩砍你的头
I'll never let Ilyn Payne take your head.
你是兰尼斯特
You're a Lannister.
你是我儿子
You're my son.
我爱她
I loved her.
谁
Who?
雪伊
Shae.
噢  提利昂
Oh, Tyrion.
-放下弩弓  -我杀了她
- Put down that crossbow. - I murdered her.
我亲手杀了她
With my own hands.
-没关系  -没关系
- It doesn't matter. - Doesn't matter?
她是个妓女
She was a whore.
-再说一遍...  -怎么样
- Say that word again... - And what?
你要在厕所里杀死自己的父亲吗
You'll kill your own father in the privy?
不
No.
你是我儿子
You're my son.
好了  别再废话了
Now, enough of this nonsense.
我是您儿子  您判了我死刑
I am your son and you sentenced me to die.
您知道不是我毒死的乔佛里
You knew I didn't poison Joffrey,
但您还是一样给我判刑
but you sentenced me all the same.
-为什么  -够了
- Why? - Enough.
我们去我卧室
We'll go back to my chambers
体面地谈谈
and speak with some dignity.
我不去  她在那里
I can't go back there. She's in there.
你害怕一个死掉的妓女吗
You're afraid of a dead whore?
你放箭
You shot me.
你不是我儿子
You're no son of mine.
我是您儿子
I am your son.
我一直都是您儿子
I have always been your son.
你做了什么
What have you done?
快走
Quickly.
相信我  朋友  我帮你走了这么远
Trust me, my friend. I brought you this far.
我要见船长
I want to see the captain.
你眼前就是
You're seeing him.
我想去北方  去长城
I want to go north to the Wall.
去不了
No, you don't.
我可以付钱
I can pay.
北方只有冰雪  战争和海盗
There is nothing in the North but ice and war and pirates.
我不需要舱房  求你了
I wouldn't need a cabin. Please.
我可以干活  擦洗甲板什么的
I could work scrubbing the floors.
我们不去北方  孩子  我们回家
I'm not going north, child. I'm going home.
-家在哪里  -自由贸易城邦布拉佛斯
- Where's home? - The Free City of Braavos.
等等  我有别的
Wait. I have something else.
多一枚银币也没区别
More silver won't make a difference.
那不是银币  是铁
It's not silver. It's iron.
这...
This...
你怎么会...
How did you--
凡人皆有一死
Valar morghulis.
凡人必须侍奉
Valar dohaeris.
当然了  你会有一间舱房
Of course, you shall have a cabin.